<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="find_in_wikipedia">Find in Wikipedia</string>
    <string name="today">Today</string>
    <string name="yesterdayy">Yesterdayy</string>
    <string name="yesterday">Yesterday</string>
    <string name="title">Title</string>
    <string name="sssssss">Sssssss</string>
    <string name="astronomical_pictures">Astronomical Pictures</string>
    <string name="Top_ten_text">Only 5% of the universe has been explored by man, and the reason is not even that there are not enough resources for more. In principle, the universe is visible by 5%, and the remaining 95% is dark matter and dark energy, which cannot be studied even with the help of the most modern technologies. Not everyone benefits from growth. If the star began to grow rapidly, the death of the celestial body is not far off. In space, even the smells are different. The fragrance of the roses that bloomed on the Discovery shuttle, although it remained pleasant, was very different from the smell of earthly roses. This fact is easy to explain: such a difference in plant odors occurs due to the difference in temperature and humidity on Earth and inside the spacecraft. The sun exceeds our planet in size by 300 thousand times. About the same difference in size in watermelon and plum. There are real giant stars in space, whose mass is 8 or more times greater than the solar mass. Such stars are called neutron stars: their density is so high that just a handful of neutron star matter will easily outweigh the highest mountains of the Earth. Celestial bodies differ from each other, but they look according to the conditions prevailing on a particular celestial body: hurricanes are raging somewhere, there is no wind at all in other places, it is very hot on some astronomical objects, eternal cold reigns on others. The relief and texture of the surface of a celestial body depend on weather conditions. And only Miranda, a satellite of Uranus, looks like a child of Frankenstein — the satellite seems to have been assembled, like a designer, from parts of different planets. Miranda looks so strange because of the collision with an asteroid. Due to the lack of gravity in space, it is impossible to boil water. The water that they try to boil, going into space, will turn into a huge bubble, moving like a wave. The two planets of the Solar System differ from the rest in complete solitude: Venus and Mercury do not have a single satellite. There are more stars in space than there are grains of sand on Earth. The brightest star in space is Sirius, it is about 22 times brighter than the Sun. To measure the brightness of Sirius in the usual cd/ m2 (lux) for earthlings will not work — astronomers measure only the brightness and luminosity of the star. The brilliance is measured in stellar magnitudes: the brilliance of Sirius is -1.44m (stellar magnitudes). The luminosity of stars depends on their distance from our planet.</string>
    <string name="facts">Top 10 interesting facts about space</string>
    <string name="spaceExp">Exploring space is much more difficult than exploring your home planet — you can\'t just take a walk and study the device of a meteorite, comet or other astronomical object.
        For experiments in the space field, people use complex manned and automatic vehicles, and astronauts are trained for such overloads that an ordinary person simply cannot withstand. But the efforts are justified: thanks to research, space is becoming clearer to humans.\n\n
        And practical research is facts beyond doubt, and here are just some of them:</string>
    <string name="facts_about_space_exploration">Facts about Space Exploration</string>
    <string name="factsExpSpace">
        1. The first person to have been in outer space is Soviet cosmonaut Alexey Leonov.
        He proved that a person can be free-floating in space and even conduct experiments and observations.\n\n
        2. Everyone has heard about space weightlessness and seen footage where astronauts easily fly inside the space station.
        But weightlessness is not only an interesting phenomenon. In zero gravity, muscles and bones become weaker due to the fact that they are almost not loaded.
        In order not to lose their health, astronauts take vitamins and do sports, for example, use a specially equipped treadmill.
        Another interesting fact is that in zero gravity, the distance between the vertebrae becomes larger, and the human growth increases. So, the record for growing an adult in space was 10 cm.\n\n
        3. The Kepler and TESS orbital telescopes were launched into space to detect and study exoplanets on which life is possible. Since 2009,
        telescopes have found thousands of suspected exoplanets, and studies have shown that life is indeed possible on about two hundred of these planets.\n\n
        4. The first successful landing on another planet took place in 1970: an apparatus was lowered to the surface of Venus, which collected important scientific data about the planet.\n\n
        5. Back in 1977, the United States launched two spacecraft with messages for representatives of other galaxies: with recordings of Earth music, human speech, and a description of the structure of an earthling\'s organism.
        The ships left the Solar System in 2007 and are still continuing their journey, using built-in instruments to explore the planets they met.\n\n</string>
    <string name="belkaStrelka">Funny fact: before the flight, the famous Squirrel and Arrow were called Alba and Marchioness, but the dog names were replaced on the instructions of the Soviet government.</string>
    <string name="gagarin">The cosmos was conquered by man in 1961, Yuri Alekseevich Gagarin became the first Soviet cosmonaut — even a child knows these facts in the post-Soviet space. Even earlier, two dogs flew into space — many people also know about this.But the very first living creature to go into space was the dog Laika. On November 3, 1957, Laika found herself in space on the Sputnik-2 spacecraft and died 6 hours later due to overheating of the capsule in which she was. In total, 65 animals served for the benefit of the Russian cosmonautics: dogs, monkeys, rabbits. Due to various malfunctions, 27 animals died. And only when the flights of four—legged astronauts began to be successful - they decided to send the first person into outer space. The first human flight into space on April 12, 1961 eventually became overgrown with rumors and legends. But there are also reliable facts related to the flight of Yuri Gagarin, confirmed by participants and witnesses of the events:</string>
    <string name="factsGagarin">1. Chief Designer Sergey Korolev could not decide for a long time who would become the first cosmonaut in the world — Yuri Gagarin or German Titov. Korolev, according to the entries in his diary, considered Titov better prepared than Gagarin.
        That is why Herman Titov flew second — the second flight was technically more difficult than the first.\n\n
        2. Not the least role in the choice of the first cosmonaut was played by the complexion of Yuri Alekseevich: The Vostok-1 had a limited payload capacity, not designed for a large person to stay in the ship. Gagarin\'s height was about 160 cm, weight — 65 kg.
        The youth of the future cosmonaut also became a plus: a pilot no older than 30 was required, Gagarin turned 27 shortly before the flight. \n\n
        3.The famous video footage of the conversation between Gagarin and Korolev before the launch was filmed not on the day of the flight, but much later.
        But the negotiations themselves repeated word for word those that actually took place on April 12, 1961. \n\n
        4. Vostok-1 worked only in autopilot mode: no one wanted to risk human life while it was unknown how the body would react to overloads. It was possible to switch to manual control mode in case of an emergency using a secret code, but Gagarin did not need this code. \n\n
        5. The first cosmonaut and the capsule in which he was landed separately. Technology has not yet allowed the ship to be equipped with a soft landing system, and Gagarin had to eject from a height of 7 km above the Earth\'s surface. The landing took place not at all on Baikonur, as planned, but as much as 1000 km to the west.\n\n</string>
    <string name="hanging_the_topic">Сhanging the topic</string>
    <string name="the_first_flight_into_space">The first flight into space</string>
    <string name="press_the_button_twice">Press the button twice</string>

</resources>